<?xml version="1.0" ?><targets><program pid="2">FeatureAlign</program><query>O[C@@H]1N[C@@H]2CC[C@H]3NCS[C@H]3[C@@H]2[C@@H]1CN[C@H]1CC[C@@H](CC1)S(O)(O)N[C@@H]1NCCCC1	http://www.rcsb.org/pdb/files/1fvv.pdb.gz
</query><species-list><species name="homo sapiens" value="2"/><species name="other species" value="0"/></species-list><target confirm="Predicted" fun="catalytic activity" geneid="983" genename="CDK1" genesyn="None" proc="cellular process" rank="1" score="1.0" simiscore="1.246" species="Homo sapiens" uniprot="A8K7C4"><name>Cyclin-Dependent Kinase 1 (CDK1)</name><function>Plays a key role in the control of the eukaryotic cell cycle by modulating the centrosome cycle as well as mitotic onset; promotes G2-M transition, and regulates G1 progress and G1-S transition via association with multiple interphase cyclins. Required in higher cells for entry into S-phase and mitosis. Phosphorylates PARVA/actopaxin, APC, AMPH, APC, BARD1, Bcl- xL/BCL2L1, BRCA2, CALD1, CASP8, CDC7, CDC20, CDC25A, CDC25C, CC2D1A, CSNK2 proteins/CKII, FZR1/CDH1, CDK7, CEBPB, CHAMP1, DMD/dystrophin, EEF1 proteins/EF-1, EZH2, KIF11/EG5, EGFR, FANCG, FOS, GFAP, GOLGA2/GM130, GRASP1, UBE2A/hHR6A, HIST1H1 proteins/histone H1, HMGA1, HIVEP3/KRC, LMNA, LMNB, LMNC, LBR, LATS1, MAP1B, MAP4, MARCKS, MCM2, MCM4, MKLP1, MYB, NEFH, NFIC, NPC/nuclear pore complex, PITPNM1/NIR2, NPM1, NCL, NUCKS1, NPM1/numatrin, ORC1, PRKAR2A, EEF1E1/p18, EIF3F/p47, p53/TP53, NONO/p54NRB, PAPOLA, PLEC/plectin, RB1, UL40/R2, RAB4A, RAP1GAP, RCC1, RPS6KB1/S6K1, KHDRBS1/SAM68, ESPL1, SKI, BIRC5/survivin, STIP1, TEX14, beta-tubulins, MAPT/TAU, NEDD1, VIM/vimentin, TK1, FOXO1, RUNX1/AML1 and RUNX2. CDK1/CDC2-cyclin-B controls pronuclear union in interphase fertilized eggs. Essential for early stages of embryonic development. During G2 and early mitosis, CDC25A/B/C-mediated dephosphorylation activates CDK1/cyclin complexes which phosphorylate several substrates that trigger at least centrosome separation, Golgi dynamics, nuclear envelope breakdown and chromosome condensation. Once chromosomes are condensed and aligned at the metaphase plate, CDK1 activity is switched off by WEE1- and PKMYT1-mediated phosphorylation to allow sister chromatid separation, chromosome decondensation, reformation of the nuclear envelope and cytokinesis. Inactivated by PKR/EIF2AK2- and WEE1-mediated phosphorylation upon DNA damage to stop cell cycle and genome replication at the G2 checkpoint thus facilitating DNA repair. Reactivated after successful DNA repair through WIP1-dependent signaling leading to CDC25A/B/C- mediated dephosphorylation and restoring cell cycle progression. In proliferating cells, CDK1-mediated FOXO1 phosphorylation at the G2-M phase represses FOXO1 interaction with 14-3-3 proteins and thereby promotes FOXO1 nuclear accumulation and transcription factor activity, leading to cell death of postmitotic neurons. The phosphorylation of beta-tubulins regulates microtubule dynamics during mitosis. NEDD1 phosphorylation promotes PLK1-mediated NEDD1 phosphorylation and subsequent targeting of the gamma-tubulin ring complex (gTuRC) to the centrosome, an important step for spindle formation. In addition, CC2D1A phosphorylation regulates CC2D1A spindle pole localization and association with SCC1/RAD21 and centriole cohesion during mitosis. The phosphorylation of Bcl- xL/BCL2L1 after prolongated G2 arrest upon DNA damage triggers apoptosis. In contrast, CASP8 phosphorylation during mitosis prevents its activation by proteolysis and subsequent apoptosis. This phosphorylation occurs in cancer cell lines, as well as in primary breast tissues and lymphocytes. EZH2 phosphorylation promotes H3K27me3 maintenance and epigenetic gene silencing. CALD1 phosphorylation promotes Schwann cell migration during peripheral nerve regeneration.</function><go_list><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000187">activation of MAPK activity</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000186">activation of MAPKK activity</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0055015">ventricular cardiac muscle cell development</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0034501">protein localization to kinetochore</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000086">G2/M transition of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0034134">toll-like receptor 2 signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0045995">regulation of embryonic development</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000083">regulation of transcription involved in G1/S phase of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0030261">chromosome condensation</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0060045">positive regulation of cardiac muscle cell proliferation</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0010628">positive regulation of gene expression</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0008063">Toll signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007411">axon guidance</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007067">mitosis</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0014075">response to amine stimulus</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0008543">fibroblast growth factor receptor signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0051437">positive regulation of ubiquitin-protein ligase activity involved in mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0051301">cell division</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0034138">toll-like receptor 3 signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007344">pronuclear fusion</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0070301">cellular response to hydrogen peroxide</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0014038">regulation of Schwann cell differentiation</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0006281">DNA repair</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0009636">response to toxin</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0006260">DNA replication</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0014070">response to organic cyclic compound</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0045740">positive regulation of DNA replication</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0035666">TRIF-dependent toll-like receptor signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0016477">cell migration</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0045087">innate immune response</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0033160">positive regulation of protein import into nucleus, translocation</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0045931">positive regulation of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0008286">insulin receptor signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0006915">apoptotic process</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0046688">response to copper ion</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0031100">organ regeneration</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0006916">anti-apoptosis</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0014823">response to activity</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0006461">protein complex assembly</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0031145">anaphase-promoting complex-dependent proteasomal ubiquitin-dependent protein catabolic process</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0048678">response to axon injury</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0046686">response to cadmium ion</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0051403">stress-activated MAPK cascade</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007173">epidermal growth factor receptor signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0034142">toll-like receptor 4 signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0048011">nerve growth factor receptor signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007265">Ras protein signal transduction</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0002755">MyD88-dependent toll-like receptor signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007569">cell aging</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000075">cell cycle checkpoint</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0045471">response to ethanol</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0042493">response to drug</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007098">centrosome cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0034130">toll-like receptor 1 signaling pathway</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007095">mitotic cell cycle G2/M transition DNA damage checkpoint</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0005829">cytosol</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0030496">midbody</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0005739">mitochondrion</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0005815">microtubule organizing center</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0005654">nucleoplasm</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0005876">spindle microtubule</go><go branch="MF" id="GO:0004693">cyclin-dependent protein kinase activity</go><go branch="MF" id="GO:0008353">RNA polymerase II carboxy-terminal domain kinase activity</go><go branch="MF" id="GO:0035173">histone kinase activity</go><go branch="MF" id="GO:0005524">ATP binding</go></go_list><pathway_list/><compounds><compound id="BD-7772" score="1.246" srcdb="BindingDB" srcid="7772"><name>Oxindole-Based Inhibitor 108</name><SMILES>c1c2c(/C(=C/Nc3ccc4c(c3)CS(=O)(=O)C4)/C(=O)N2)c2c(c1)ncs2</SMILES><effect></effect><activities><activity type="IC50" value="31"/></activities></compound></compounds></target><target confirm="Predicted" fun="catalytic activity" geneid="1017" genename="CDK2" genesyn="CDKN2" proc="regulation of biological process" rank="2" score="0.0" simiscore="1.214" species="Homo sapiens" uniprot="O75100"><name>CDK2</name><function>Serine/threonine-protein kinase involved in the control of the cell cycle; essential for meiosis, but dispensable for mitosis. Phosphorylates CTNNB1, USP37, p53/TP53, NPM1, CDK7, RB1, BRCA2, MYC, NPAT, EZH2. Interacts with cyclins A, B1, B3, D, or E. Triggers duplication of centrosomes and DNA. Acts at the G1-S transition to promote the E2F transcriptional program and the initiation of DNA synthesis, and modulates G2 progression; controls the timing of entry into mitosis/meiosis by controlling the subsequent activation of cyclin B/CDK1 by phosphorylation, and coordinates the activation of cyclin B/CDK1 at the centrosome and in the nucleus. Crucial role in orchestrating a fine balance between cellular proliferation, cell death, and DNA repair in human embryonic stem cells (hESCs). Activity of CDK2 is maximal during S phase and G2; activated by interaction with cyclin E during the early stages of DNA synthesis to permit G1-S transition, and subsequently activated by cyclin A2 (cyclin A1 in germ cells) during the late stages of DNA replication to drive the transition from S phase to mitosis, the G2 phase. EZH2 phosphorylation promotes H3K27me3 maintenance and epigenetic gene silencing. Phosphorylates CABLES1 (By similarity). Cyclin E/CDK2 prevents oxidative stress-mediated Ras-induced senescence by phosphorylating MYC. Involved in G1-S phase DNA damage checkpoint that prevents cells with damaged DNA from initiating mitosis; regulates homologous recombination-dependent repair by phosphorylating BRCA2, this phosphorylation is low in S phase when recombination is active, but increases as cells progress towards mitosis. In response to DNA damage, double-strand break repair by homologous recombination a reduction of CDK2-mediated BRCA2 phosphorylation. Phosphorylation of RB1 disturbs its interaction with E2F1. NPM1 phosphorylation by cyclin E/CDK2 promotes its dissociates from unduplicated centrosomes, thus initiating centrosome duplication. Cyclin E/CDK2-mediated phosphorylation of NPAT at G1-S transition and until prophase stimulates the NPAT- mediated activation of histone gene transcription during S phase. Required for vitamin D-mediated growth inhibition by being itself inactivated. Involved in the nitric oxide- (NO) mediated signaling in a nitrosylation/activation-dependent manner. USP37 is activated by phosphorylation and thus triggers G1-S transition. CTNNB1 phosphorylation regulates insulin internalization.</function><go_list><go branch="BP" id="GO:0071732">cellular response to nitric oxide</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0051301">cell division</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000084">S phase of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007089">traversing start control point of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0051439">regulation of ubiquitin-protein ligase activity involved in mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0016572">histone phosphorylation</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0006275">regulation of DNA replication</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0008284">positive regulation of cell proliferation</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007126">meiosis</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007596">blood coagulation</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0051298">centrosome duplication</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007067">mitosis</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000086">G2/M transition of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0060968">regulation of gene silencing</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000085">G2 phase of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000082">G1/S transition of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0000216">M/G1 transition of mitotic cell cycle</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0031145">anaphase-promoting complex-dependent proteasomal ubiquitin-dependent protein catabolic process</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0007265">Ras protein signal transduction</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0006977">DNA damage response, signal transduction by p53 class mediator resulting in cell cycle arrest</go><go branch="BP" id="GO:0006260">DNA replication</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0005813">centrosome</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0005829">cytosol</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0005768">endosome</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0000307">cyclin-dependent protein kinase holoenzyme complex</go><go branch="CC" id="GO:0015030">Cajal body</go><go branch="MF" id="GO:0005524">ATP binding</go><go branch="MF" id="GO:0004693">cyclin-dependent protein kinase activity</go></go_list><pathway_list/><compounds><compound id="BD-50145876" score="1.214" srcdb="BindingDB" srcid="50145876"><name>CHEMBL85101</name><SMILES>c1(c2c([nH]c1O)ccc1c2scn1)/C=N/c1ccc(S(=O)(=O)NCCO)cc1</SMILES><effect></effect><activities><activity type="IC50" value="4.7"/></activities></compound></compounds></target><fun-list><function name="catalytic activity" value="2"/></fun-list><proc-list><process name="cellular process" value="1"/><process name="regulation of biological process" value="1"/></proc-list></targets>